Andrei Tonkikh

Phone: +7(904)856-51-29

Email: andrei.tonkikh@gmail.com

Summary

GitHub profile: xosmig
LinkedIn® profile: andrei-tonkikh

I am a 4th year student studying computer science with focus on cloud computing. I'm fascinated by distributed systems and multiprocessor programming as well as by other kinds of system software such as operating systems and databases. My long term goal is to do research and development in one or several of the above-mentioned areas.

Education -

St. Petersburg branch of the Higher School of Economics

2018 - Present

BS in Computer Science (continuing) Graduating July 2019

St. Petersburg Academic University

2015 - 2018

BS in Computer Science

Work Experience –

Junior Software Engineer at Yandex

January 2019 - Present

Enhancing job scheduling algorithms for YT. YT is a distributed batch-processing platform based on Map-Reduce paradigm and running on many thousands of servers. In particular, I'm trying to deal with the problem of resource underutilization caused by fragmentation.

SWE Intern at Yandex

July - December 2018

Investigated the problem of resource fragmentation on YT clusters. Improved the scheduling simulator – a tool to simulate the traces from the production scheduler and evaluate scheduling strategies. This project included a good amount of concurrent C++ code. The challenge was to make it efficient yet easy to understand and maintain afterwards.

SRE Intern at Google

Summer 2017

Was part of Traffic Team SRE in London. Improved observability of Google Cloud Engine. Designed, implemented and integrated a library for reporting statistics from test instances of GCE components.

Most Relevant University Courses

Fall 2018 External Memory Algorithms, Big Data Software Engineering
 Spring 2018 Parallel Programming, Containerization, Computer Networks, Compillers
 Fall 2017 Linux Kernel, Databases, Statistics, Software Engineering
 2016 – 17 Operating Systems, Functional Programming in Haskell, Java
 2015 – 16 Algorithms and Data Structures, C++, Linux Administration

Courseworks include, but are not limited to, writing *multi-threaded OS-kernel* and a simple *containerization* utility in Rust, creating simple linux kernel modules in C, implementing a very basic *mapreduce framework* in Kotlin, a x86 compiler in OCaml, and a *multiplayer 3D action game for Android* in Java.

Programming Languages

Strongest: C++, C

Comfortable: Go, Kotlin, Java, Rust, Python, Bash

Limited Experience: Scala, R, Haskell, OCaml

Open Source Contribution –

Packer Builder for VMware vSphere

Fall 2017

Automated creation of virtual machines and OS installation in vSphere environment.

github.com/jetbrains-infra/packer-builder-vsphere

Rust Standard Collections Library

Spring 2016

Contributed to the implementations of B-Tree and Binary Heap in rust standard library. github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/33947 and github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/32987